James Hargreaves

Birchwood, Lochgoilhead, Argyll, PA24 8AJ Mobile: 07792942935, E-mail: jameshargreaves1@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am an enthusiastic and highly motivated individual with a passion for learning.

I have spent the last five years learning to write code in various languages alongside running an e-commerce business which we have now decided to close down.

Along with daily use of HTML and CSS over the last ten years I gained my first taste of programming when I became interested in writing automated financial trading algorithms around five years ago in C / C++.

Having absolutely loved this period of learning I decided that I would like to continue and decided to enrol on the notoriously challenging CS50 computer science course remotely via Harvard's online portal to give me a more rounded knowledge of computer science and exposure to other languages and technologies including C, Python, Javascript and SQL amongst others.

The course was extremely challenging and greatly helped in rounding out my knowledge of programming including data structures, encryption and low level programming.

During Covid, with the downturn our business experienced I decided to look at software / web development seriously as a future career and started to focus heavily on learning Javascript and it's associated technologies.

I have increased my knowledge to cover React as well as NodeJS and Express and have since gained experience with GraphQL, MongoDB and Dart/Flutter from a six month internship at a family member's SAAS startup.

I continue to love the challenge of learning and increasing my knowledge in this field. My experience in the industry last year only further cemented the fact that I feel that development is where my future career lies. I bring a host of transferable skills from my previous roles including excellent interpersonal skills having always been client facing and a great eye for detail having worked in a number of regulated roles.

EDUCATION

2023 Harvard via Edx

CS50X - introduction to Computer Science - Pass 100%

1990 to 1995 Clitheroe Royal Grammar School

GCSE grade A* Science
GCSE grade A* Science
GCSE grade A Mathematics
GCSE grade A English

GCSE grade **A** English Literature
GCSE grade **A** Design and Technology

GCSE grade **A** French GCSE grade **B** History

GCSE grade **B** Art and Design
GCSE grade **B** Physical Education

1995 to 1997 Clitheroe Royal Grammar School Sixth Form College

A-LEVEL grade **C** Business Studies
A-LEVEL grade **C** Design and Technology

A-LEVEL grade **C** Biology

A-LEVEL grade C General Studies

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dot On Technologies 6 Month Internship - Junior Software Developer 2022

I approached Dot On for an internship position to get some real industry experience and further develop my skills in a broad range of technologies whilst working as part of a development team.

This experience was invaluable as it exposed me to all parts of the development process from back-end through to UI whist collaborating with a team using Jira / Git / Bitbucket - experience I could not have gained working on my own projects.

My tasks included:

Refactoring existing codebase and adding new features as required.

Writing unit / integration tests in Javascript and Dart using Jest and Dart's built in testing suite.

Working with a MongoDB database using NodeJS / GraphQL / Apollo Server.

Improving documentation where possible and making sure code comments are up to date and inline with company specifications.

Working with a back end API and associated documentation / specification.

Technologies used:

Javascript, Dart, Flutter, NodeJS, GraphQL, MongoDB, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Sourcetree

Sparkle Boutique
April 2012 - Present
Partner, E-commerce business

- Dealing with all aspects of day to day running of a small e-commerce business.
- Using HTML and CSS to create product listings and templates.
- Uploading products to website / online marketplaces.
- Maintaining detailed records both for internal assessment as well as external bodies such as HMRC.
- Producing daily sales reports and monitoring stock levels across the business.
- Dealing with customers and providing detailed product information and quotations.
- Responsible for the entire logistics process from customer enquiry through to dispatch of orders.

2007 - 2012 Royal Bank of Scotland / Countrywide / Homeloan Partnership Mortgage Advisor

2005 - 2007 Blue Arrow Ltd Commercial Recruitment Consultant

2000 - 2005
RAPID IT Distribution / Computer Commodities
IT Technical Support / Account Manager

<u>INTERESTS</u>

I enjoy an active lifestyle and enjoy walking, cycling and keeping physically fit. I like to keep an active mind and enjoy reading about current events and watching documentaries.